Finding Aid for Information Technology Division (University of Michigan) publications, 1971-1999
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Information Technology Division (University of Michigan) publications 1971-1999, 1985-1999
University of Michigan. Information Technology Division.
5 linear feet
0070 Bimu 2
Includes bibliographies, brochures, bulletins, manuals, newsletters, proceedings, and reports from the Information Technology Division. Also contains publications from the Center for Information Technology Integration, Consulting and Support Services, Information Technology General Council, Merit Computer Network, Office of Administrative Systems, Information Systems and Services, Office of Instructional Technology, Telecommunications Systems, University Information Systems and User Services.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The record group was transferred from the Information Technology Division (Donor No. 7873 ) in several accessions beginning in July 1990.
Periodic additions to the records expected.
The publications are open for research.
See the history in finding aid for Information Technology Division (University of Michigan) records
The Information Technology Division began publishing many of the Computing Center's manuals and newsletters after 1989 and 1990. Before those dates, they may be found in the publications group Computing Center Publications. After the transfer of Computing Center activities to the Information Technology Division, the researcher may find those publication in Information Technology Division Publications. Notes are made to this effect throughout the container lists. Please consult both finding aids.
The ITD Publications subgroup (5 linear feet) is divided into two series: Unit Publications and Sub-Unit Publications.
Subjects:
University of Michigan. Information Technology Division.; University of Michigan. Consulting and Support Services.; University of Michigan. Office of Administrative Systems.; University of Michigan. Information Systems and Services.; University of Michigan. Computing Center.; University of Michigan. Center for Information Technology Integration.; University of Michigan. Information Technology General Council.; University of Michigan. M-Pathways Project.; MERIT Computer Network.; University of Michigan. Office of Instructional Technology.; University of Michigan. Telecommunication Systems.; University of Michigan. University Information Systems and User Services.
Contributors:
University of Michigan. Computing Center.; University of Michigan. Center for Information Technology Integration.; University of Michigan. Consulting and Support Services.; University of Michigan. Information Technology General Council.; MERIT Computer Network.; University of Michigan. Office of Instructional Technology.; University of Michigan. Telecommunication Systems.; University of Michigan. University Information Systems and User Services.; University of Michigan. M-Pathways Project.; University of Michigan. Office of Administrative Systems.
Genre Terms:
Bibliographies.; Pamphlets.; Bulletins.; Manuals.; Newsletters.; Proceedings.; Reports.
- Unit Publications
  The series Unit Publications includes brochures, manuals, newsletters, proceedings, and reports dating from the years 1971 to 1994. The newsletter Information Technology Digest (1992-1998) was created from the merger of a Computing Center publication, U-M Computing News, and two publications from the Office of Administrative Systems, Communication Lines and the Newsletter (also published by Telecommunications Systems and University Information Systems, respectively). Information Technology Digest was discontinued in 1998 and replaced by the e-mail newsletter, News from ITD. News from ITD is printed out, and issues can be found in this series.
  This series also contains a number of manuals which describe the computing environment at the University of Michigan, as well as detailed instructions on how to sign on, how to get help when needed, the proper use policy, and instructions about specific programs and software. These manuals include the New User Guide, and the Reference, Tutorial, and Step-by-Step series. Each of these titles is found in the Unit Publications series, though one or another sub-unit may have contributed to an individual issue's publication.
  - Bibliographies
    - 1995 & undated (Box 1)
  - Brochures
    - Computer KickOff, 1986-1995 (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous 1995 & undated (Box 1)
    - Window into Information Technology at the University of Michigan, January 1989 (Box 1)
  - Bulletins
    - Non-Credit Computing Courses on Campus, 1990-1999, 5 folders (Box 1)
      (for earlier issues, please see Computing Center Publications)
  - Flyers
    - 1989-1997 & undated (Box 1)
  - Manuals
    - Computing at the University of Michigan: An Orientation Guide for Parents, Summer 1995 (Box 1)
    - Computing Changes for Fall Term '96: A Guide to UMCE [University of Michigan Computing Environment] Services for Faculty, Staff and Students, September 1996 (Box 1)
    - Computing Handbook, 1995-1996 (Box 1)
    - Info Tech Guide: Overview of Computing Services for Students, Faculty and Staff, 1994 (Box 1)
    - New User Guide, 1990-1993 (Box 1)
    - Reference
      - nos. R1039-R1218 1990-1995, 5 folders (Box 1)
      - Focus Series, nos. R1200-R1218 1991 (Box 1)
    - Step-by-Step, nos. S4001-S4191 1994-1996, 2 folders (Box 1)
    - Tutorials
      - Getting it on tape--Introduction to Magnetic Tapes (Tutorial no. T7002), October 1993 (Box 1)
      - Getting started--Introduction to MTS [Michigan Terminal System] (Tutorial no. T7003), July 1991 (Box 1)
      - Getting connected--Introduction to Terminals and Microcomputers (Tutorial no. T7005), March 1990 (Box 1)
      - nos. T7008-T7041 1990-1995, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Maps
    - Computing on Campus, 1993-1997 (Box 1)
  - Minutes
    - BAT Minutes, 1995-1996 (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous
    - 1993-1996 (Box 1)
  - Newsletters
    - Burger Bytes, 1989-1990 (Box 1)
    - Information Technology Digest
      (supersedes U-M Computing News (see Computer Center Publications), Communication Lines under the Sub-Unit Telecommunications Systems, and Newsletter under the Sub-Unit University Information Systems; precedes News @ ITD)
      - 1992-1993, 4 folders (Box 1)
      - 1994-1998, 5 folders (Box 2)
    - ITD News, 1989-1990 (Box 2)
    - ITD Reorganization News, 1995 (Box 2)
    - ITD Transition Newsletter, 1996 (Box 2)
    - Inside ITD News, 1990-1991 (Box 2)
    - News @ ITD, 1996-1998, 3 folders (Box 2)
      (precedes News from ITD)
    - News from ITD, 1998-1999 (Box 2)
      (supersedes News @ ITD)
  - Newspapers
    - The University Record (special edition), Education for the 21st Century: Information Technology, December 12, 1988 (Box 2)
  - Proceedings
    - Seminar on Information Technology in Higher Education, 1985 (Box 2)
  - Reports
    - Guiding Principles for the Transition from the Present MTS Computing Environment to a Future Distributed Computing Environment, 1992 (Box 2)
    - ITD Project Status Report, 1995-1999, 4 folders (Box 2)
- Sub-Unit Publications
  The Sub-Unit Publications series consists of printed materials produced by the sub-units within ITD. The Center for Information Technology Integration produces the bulletin CITI Course Catalog, and the newsletter CITI Lights. The M-Pathways Monthly Status Report can be found in this series. There are also annual reports, newsletters, and monthly status reports from the Office of Administrative Systems, which became University Information Systems. The units under the Office of Administrative Systems include Telecommunications Systems, Data Systems Center and Information Systems and Services.
  - Advanced Workstation Lab
    - Schedules 1989 (Box 3)
  - Campus Computing Sites
    - Brochures 1995 (Box 3)
  - Center for Information Technology Integration
    - Brochures Undated (Box 3)
    - Bulletins
      - CITI Course Catalog, 1994-1996, 3 folders (Box 3)
    - Newsletters
      - CITI Lights, 1993-1994, 2 folders (Box 3)
    - Press Releases 1992-1994 (Box 3)
    - Proposals
      - Institutional File System Project, 1990 (Box 3)
  - CIESIN
    - Newsletters
      - CIESIN Info Tech News Notes, 1991 (Box 3)
  - Consulting and Support Services
    - Announcements
      - Information Center Users Group 1989-1991 (Box 3)
    - Calendars
      - Using Your Computer: Learning Opportunities for L.S.& A. Faculty and Staff, 1992 (Box 3)
    - Directories
      - Computing Resources on Campus, 1986-1992, 2 folders (Box 3)
    - Manuals
      - Data Access Overview, 1993 (Box 3)
      - Pagemaker Basic Skills, 1991 (Box 3)
    - Newsletters
      - IC User Notes, 1987-1993 (Box 3)
    - Programs
      - MacWorkplace: A Showcase for Creative Solutions, 1991 (Box 3)
    - Reports
      - ITD Priority Services Review Perceived Value Study Report 1991 (Box 3)
  - Education Services
    - Miscellaneous 1995 (Box 3)
  - Future Computing Environment
    - Reports
      - Moving from an MTS-Centered Computing Environment to a Distributed Computing Environment: Plans and Request for Comment, 1994 (Box 3)
  - Information Technology General Council
    - Directories
      - The University of Michigan Information Technology General Council Membership Directory, 1990-1991 (Box 3)
    - Newsletters
      - IT Clipboard, 1988-1992 (Box 3)
    - Programs
      - Agenda: ITGC Meeting, 1990 (Box 3)
    - Reports
      - ITGC Action Group on Electronic Forms Report, January 1991 (Box 3)
      - Response to Issues Raised by the Information Technology General Council, October 1990 (Box 3)
    - Surveys
      - ITGC Mission Statement Review Survey [Draft], May 1992 (Box 3)
  - M-Pathways
    - Brochures circa 1997 (Box 3)
    - Newsletters
      - Trans-Express, 1997 (Box 3)
    - Reports
      - M-Pathways Monthly Status Report, 1997-1999 (Box 3)
  - Managing Diversity Program
    - Brochures circa 1991-1994 (Box 3)
    - Manuals
      - Managing Diversity Concepts and Principles Seminar Training Manual, 1993 (Box 3)
      - Organizational Culture Analysis Training Participant Manual: ITD Leadership Team, Summer 1994 (Box 3)
    - Newsletters
      - Managing Diversity, 1993-1995 (Box 3)
    - Reports
      - Cultural Audit Results, December 1993 (Box 3)
      - Organizational Culture Analysis: ITD--The University of Michigan, Submitted by The American Institute for Managing Diversity, Inc., 1994 (Box 3)
  - Office of Administrative Systems
    - Annual Reports
      - Fourth Annual Progress Report and Development Plan, June 1977 (Box 3)
    - Brochures undated (Box 3)
    - Manuals
      - Handbook of Information Retrieval Systems, 1985 (Box 3)
    - Newsletters
      - Newsletter
        - 1977 vol. 6, no. 1-3 (Box 3)
        - 1982-1989 vol 8-18, 5 folders (Box 4)
          (for later issues see University Information Systems, Newsletters Newsletter)
      - RapAround, 1988-1989 (Box 4)
    - Proposals
      - A Proposal and Detailed Design for Enhancement of Administrative Systems Data and Office Communications Network, 1982 (Box 4)
    - Reports
      - Introduction to the Office of Administrative Systems: An Overview of OAS Services and Products, 1986 (Box 4)
      - The Office of Administrative Systems Presentation to Executive Computing Committee, 1989 (Box 4)
      - The University of Michigan Administrative Data Processing Study: Management Presentation, prepared by Nolan, Norton & Company, October 1978 (Box 4)
    - Data Systems Center
      - Annual Reports
        - Annual Report, 1971/72 (Box 4)
      - Brochures
        - CRISP: Computer Registration Involving Student Participation, 1975 (Box 4)
      - Histories
        - History, Function and Organization of DSC, 1973 (Box 4)
      - Manuals
        - The ISPF Editor and SDSF: An Introductory Guide, 1984 (Box 4)
        - Project Management Guide, 1973 (Box 4)
          (for earlier issues, see Computing Center Publications)
        - RAMIS: An Introductory Guide, undated (Box 4)
        - Using THOR for Producing Text with UMFORMAT, 1981 (Box 4)
      - Newsletters
        - Newsletter, 1973 (Box 4)
      - Reports
        - 1982/83 Rate Analysis, June 1982 (Box 4)
        - 1983/84 Rate Analysis, June 1983 (Box 4)
        - Presentation on Hardware/Software Facilities Utilized for the On-Line Data Base Environment, May 1974 (Box 4)
        - System Statistics with Year-to-Date Totals, 1986 (Box 4)
      - Songbooks
        - DSC Songbook [Christmas songs], undated (Box 4)
      - Student Data Systems
        - Proposals
          - Admissions Project: Detail Systems Design Specification, January 1984 (Box 4)
          - Admissions Project: General Systems Design Specification July 1980 (Box 4)
          - Grade Processing Project: Detailed System Design Summary
            - Part I, May 1982 (Box 4)
            - Part II, February 1982 (Box 4)
    - Development and Communication
      - Reports
        - Alumni Report, 1984/85 (Box 4)
    - Information Center
      - Flyers undated (Box 4)
      - Manuals
        - Emc2 Quick and Easy Reference Guide, 1989 (Box 4)
        - The Student Profile Data Guide 1987 (Box 4)
      - Newsletters
        - Office Systems Newsbriefs, vol. 2-5, 1983-1986 (Box 4)
    - Information Systems and Services
      - Manuals
        - New Version of Emc2, the DSC Electronic Mail System--Conversion Implementation: 07/29/89, July 1989 (Box 4)
      - Newsletters
        - Wangnet System Bulletin, 1986 (Box 4)
    - Management Information System
      - Annual Reports
        - Progress Report and Development Plan, 1979-1983 (Box 4)
    - Telecommunications Systems
      - Annual Reports
        - Progress Report and Development Plan, 1985-1989 (Box 4)
      - Manuals
        - Personal Line Telephone User's Guide, September 1985 (Box 4)
        - Voice Mail User's Guide, 1987 (Box 4)
      - Newsletters
        - Communication Lines, Volumes 1-6, 1984-1989, 4 folders (Box 4)
          (precedes "Sub-Unit Publications, Telecommunications Systems, Newsletters Communication Lines")
        - Family Housing Newsline, 1986 (Box 4)
  - Office of Instructional Technology
    - Bibliographies (Box 5)
      - Works in Progress: Projects from the Office of Instructional Technology, 1992-1997 (Box 5)
    - Miscellaneous 1989-1991, undated (Box 5)
  - Office of Policy Development and Education
    - Brochures
      - Think About It, 1995, undated (Box 5)
  - Software Site License Committee
    - Reports
      - Issue Analysis and Recommendations: Negotiating, Administering, Distributing and Supporting Site Licensed Software at the University of Michigan, January 1990 (Box 5)
  - Telecommunications Systems
    - Manuals
      - UMTel Rate Guide, 1987/88 (Box 5)
    - Newsletters
      - Communication Lines, vol. 7-8, 1990-1991 (Box 5)
        (supersedes "Sub-Unit Publications, Office of Administrative Systems, Telecommunications Systems, Newsletters Communication Lines;" precedes Information Technology Digest),
  - University Information Systems
    - Manuals
      - DB2 Security Guidelines (Draft), January 1990 (Box 5)
      - System Development Methodology: Define, Design, Construct, Implement, 1990 (Box 5)
      - Technical Bulletin, no. 125, 1994 (Box 5)
    - Newsletters
      - Newsletter, vol. 19-20, 1990-1991 (Box 5)
        (for earlier issues, see Office of Administrative Systems, Newsletters Newsletter)
      - RapAround, 1990 (Box 5)
    - Organizational Chart
      - UIS Plan, 1990 (Box 5)
    - Reports
      - University Information Systems Interview Summary Report, 1993 (Box 5)
      - UIS Status Report, 1994-1995, 2 folders (Box 5)
    - Surveys
      - Survey Results: "What are the inhibitors to having UIS move forward in distributed computing?" 1995 (Box 5)
    - Data Access Pilot Project
      - Reports
        - Financial Pilot Tables, May 1990 (Box 5)
        - Oracle Tools and Financial Tables Demonstration, June 1990 (Box 5)
        - Project Report, September 1990 (Box 5)
    - Information Systems and Services
      - Departmental Systems and Services
        - Reports
          - Distributed Computing: The Role of Departmental Systems and Services, circa 1990 (Box 5)
    - Standards Quality Improvement Team
      - Proposals 1993-1994 (Box 5)
  - U-M Online
    - Brochure 1996 (Box 5)
  - UMTV
    - Brochures 1997 (Box 5)
  - User Services
    - Manuals
      - Guide to Computing on Campus, 1993-1994 (Box 5)
    - Miscellaneous
      - ITD Communications: 1993 publications, reports, documentation, and promotional materials produced by the User Services Communications Group for the Information Technology Division, 1994, 4 folders (Box 5)
    - Surveys
      - Needs Assessment, 1987 (Box 5)